Iason Somarakis

Greece



jason_somarakis@protonmail.com



linkedin.com/in/iason-somarakis-493474100

Summary

lason Somarakis works as a senior security engineer, focusing on research, development and application of security solutions. With hands-on experience in penetration testing methodologies and tools, virtualization and containerization frameworks and machine learning algorithms for enhanced proactive and reactive security mechanisms. Furthermore, he has an up to date view of the technological landscape and a diverse toolkit of programming languages, networking, and infrastructure as a code frameworks.

lason's research interests focus on two types of security assessments, cyber range training and penetration testing; specifically, asset and threat emulation technologies for cyber range training and offensive technologies for penetration testing.

Last but not least, his personal interests include capture the flag activities, privacy related topics, cryptocurrencies, and reading novels.

Experience

Sphynx Technology Solutions

Aug 2021 - Present (5 months +)

Responsibilities:

- Managing and Designing SPHYNX's Cyber Range capabilities
- Developing the emulation (i.e., asset and threat emulation) and infrastructure orchestration mechanisms of SPHYNX's Cyber Range
- Developing training content for SPHYNX's Cyber Range
- Managing, Designing and Developing SPHYNX's Penetration Testing capabilities
- SPHYNX's designated penetration tester
- Managing, Contributing and Developing on RESIST EU Project
- Managing, Contributing and Developing on HOLOBALANCE EU Project
- · Managing and Contributing on AERAS EU Project

Security Engineer

Sphynx Technology Solutions

Jan 2020 - Aug 2021 (1 year 8 months)

Responsibilities:

- Designing SPHYNX's Cyber Range capabilities
- Developing the emulation (i.e., asset and threat) and infrastructure orchestration mechanisms of SPHYNX's Cyber Range
- Managing, Designing and Developing SPHYNX's Penetration Testing capabilities
- SPHYNX's designated penetration tester
- Managing, Contributing and Developing on RESIST EU Project
- · Managing, Contributing and Developing on HOLOBALANCE EU Project
- Contributing and Developing on Threat Arrest EU Project

Software Engineer

Sphynx Technology Solutions

Apr 2018 - Jan 2020 (1 year 10 months)

Responsibilities:

- Managing, Designing and Developing SPHYNX's Penetration Testing capabilities
- SPHYNX's designated penetration tester
- · Managing, Contributing and Developing on RESIST EU Project
- · Managing, Contributing and Developing on HOLOBALANCE EU Project
- Contributing and Developing on THREAT ARREST EU Project
- Contributing and Developing on SEMIOTICS EU Project

IT Support Technician

Curvature

Apr 2016 - Dec 2016 (9 months)

Responsibilities:

- Uphold all aspects of Curvature's Information Security Management systems.
- Assist staff with the installation, configuration, and ongoing usability of desktop computers, peripheral equipment and software within established standards and guidelines.
- Assist in the design and deployment of a standard OS and Software images
- Works with vendor support contacts to resolve technical problems with desktop computing equipment and software.
- Manages Help Desk request queue (Ticketing System, Knowledgebase, and Asset Management).
- Trains and orients staff on use of hardware and software.
- Performs upgrades on systems to ensure longevity.
- Assists in maintaining Voice related services

IT Support /Network administrator Trainee

Curvature

Oct 2015 - Apr 2016 (7 months)

- Uphold all aspects of Curvature's Information Security Management systems.•
- Activities require interaction with application software and operating systems to diagnose and resolve problems.
- Assist staff with the installation, configuration, and ongoing usability of desktop computers, peripheral equipment and software within established standards and guidelines.
- Assist in the design and deployment of a standard OS and Software images
- Works with vendor support contacts to resolve technical problems with desktop computing equipment and software.
- Manages Help Desk request queue (Ticketing System, Knowledgebase, and Asset Management).
- Trains and orients staff on use of hardware and software.
- · Performs upgrades on systems to ensure longevity.
- Assists in maintaining Voice related services

Technician's assistant / IT support

Ipekat IKE

Jun 2013 - 2015 (2 years 7 months)

Responsibilities:

· Management and maintenance of IT equipment

Education

City, University of London

PhD, Computer and Information Systems Security/Information Assurance 2019 - 2023

Asset and Threat Emulation for Cybersecurity Training at School of Mathematics, Computer Sciences & Engineering

Technological Educational Institute of Crete

Computer Software Engineering

2010 - 2018

Worked on several projects mainly on Python, JAVA, C++, Matlab.

Licenses & Certifications

U EU Scholarship - Android Development for Beginners - Udacity

Neural Networks and Deep Learning - Coursera AX7EC2SQX9KD

The Ultimate Ethical Hacking Course 2017 - Udemy **UC-XRNM4HIJ**

IDS/IPS - Cybrary SC-c61f1a18c3-a3b75

- Incident Handling Training Cource at NIS 2018 ENISA-FORTH
- Penetration Testing and Ethical Hacking Cybrary C-c61f1a18c3-a2f5b1
- Python for Security Professionals Cybrary C-c61f1a18c3-a9ae436
- Entry Level Training of Cyber-MAR project CyberMAR
- Offensive Pentesting Learning Path TryHackMe THM-T8YUMV0S6S

Skills

Software Development • Penetration Testing • Virtualization • Containerization • Research • Vagrant (Software) • Ansible • Docker Products • VirtualBox • Python (Programming Language)

Honors & Awards

Employee of the year - Sphynx Technology Solutions
Dec 2020

Junior engineer of the year